Okay.
In this lecture we're
going to talk about Kubernetes scheduling.
Look, take a look at the load
balancing lecture that we did
and realize that scale, scaling
and load balancing
need to work hand in hand,
where the load balancer
has a lot of the metrics
that you need in order
to feed into the scaler and the scaler.
When it spins things up,
you need to make sure
that those microservices
are being registered
with the load balancer.
So it's a it's a great,
integration that that can really, improve
resiliency, scalability and reliability.
So take a look at that. Okay.
So the idea here is that Kubernetes,
has the ability to scale up,
more pods and more microservices
to handle the workloads that come
and not just scale up, but also scale down
to save money on resources,
because in the cloud you pay,
you pay for resources,
whether they're being used or not.
So you want to
if you're not using resource, you want to
tear it down as best as you can.
So let's take a look
at the differences in,
scalability opportunities with Kubernetes.
So primarily with Kubernetes
you're talking about pod
autoscaling because a pod is
where these microservices are running
or the individual containers are running.
Now I can have multiple containers
running in the same pod.
Typically not multiple replicas
of the same container.
That just doesn't give you
that resilience that you want.
But there's helper containers and tasks
that run in, in, in individual pods.
So the idea here is that
I can adjust the number of pod replicas,
meaning I've got the same exact
microservice running across
multiple pods, in, in your cluster.
And I can use different metrics
to determine
when to spin up new pods
and when to tear them down.
I normally set a minimum and a maximum,
and then I can set some kind of,
thresholds in
that are built that I need to do it.
I also have the capability
of doing some custom scheduling there
if I want as well, using external metrics
or whatever the case may be so built in
right now, the gun CPU utilization
is the number one thing that they use.
Here's
an example of this horizontal scaling,
which means I'm replicating
the same pod over and over again
so that HPA horizontal pod scheduling.
All right.
So auto scaling the pods
horizontally right.
In this case here I am
defining the minimum number of replicas
that I have.
This gives me reliability and scalability
right.
Minimum replica.
And this is two and the maximum is ten.
So I put in there exactly
the range that I want to do it.
The goal here is to have it
the minimum number amount as possible.
Most of the schedulers do that already
where they're, hey,
I'm scaling to the minimum amount
and I will only max out of the max.
And when I can I'm going to drop off.
Different replicas
as I need as I don't need them anymore.
So in this case
here, I'm saying that there is an average
utilization that I want to stay at,
which is 60.
Once I go above 60, I'm going to spin up
another replica to decrease, the,
workload across all of the different,
pods that I have or microservices
that I have.
When it drops well below that, it's
going to start looking at
can I get rid of a pod or not?
So to save up on those resources.
Okay.
I also have vertical pod autoscaler.
Now this is a little bit different
because vertical means
that maybe I have a set of microservices.
They're all running in the same pod.
Maybe they're running in different pods
that when I need more,
I can, if I, if I have a lot of requests
coming in that require
five different types of microservices,
I can scale those up on demand,
and then I can also evict them,
get rid of them as I as
I don't need them anymore.
Right.
So there's, lots of options with, the VPA,
the vertical and pod scaler.
I can set up really complex workflows
that will only create the pods
on demand as they need to saving resources
that go along.
I've had some workflows,
have over 100 microservices in IT
that do very specific things.
They're more task
oriented, type of microservices.
I don't want those things hanging around.
So in this case,
when they're done, I don't
I don't create a new replica of them.
And and no one time in the workflow
or all 100 of them running,
probably more like only 5 or 10
or running at a time.
All different microservices.
I can have multiple replicas
and all that stuff.
So it's great for stateful workflows,
reducing that overprovision
that, that, can happen sometimes.
Okay.
Cluster autoscaling.
So this is when I'm actually adding
more nodes to the cluster.
This is these tools out there are great
if my cluster is being overwhelmed
and I want to add more nodes
to the cluster.
This ties in a lot with the cloud service
providers, auto scalers,
where I can go and ask those autoscaler
saying I need more nodes.
Those nodes can be dropped in and torn
out of the cluster and dynamically,
when a node is removed from a cluster,
it takes some time to bring it back in.
So you have to be careful
that you're not thrashing your cluster
by saying, hey, I take that node out
and I want it back in now.
I want it out because I want it back in
because you're right on a threshold.
So be careful
that when you're setting these things up.
But very beneficial, especially for saving
money on running resources in the cloud.
So take a look
at these cluster arm scalers.
All right.
Manual.
There's there's lots of different ways
that I can scale.
I can force a scale manually by,
using kube
controller scale, deploy me on the back
end and see how many replicas I want.
I can force the number of replicas
that I want,
or I can use cron jobs to say,
you know what?
I know?
Every night I run a batch process
in my Kubernetes cluster that runs
all my general ledger accounting stuff.
And maybe I know
from experience and experimentation
that I'm going to need,
five more clusters during that time
so I can set up a cron job
to handle this for me.
And that's a great way to go.
I can scale it up,
and then when I know they're done,
I can scale them back down if I want to.
Or I can let the autoscaler say, hey,
I'm above the I'm below the thresholds
dramatically.
I've been there for a while.
I'm going to scale those back down.
So there are reasons
why you would want to preemptively scale
up, instead of just waiting
until you meet the thresholds.
And that's to handle big loads
that you know are coming in.
Okay.
Best practices,
make sure that you set reasonable
and sensible min and max,
replicas that you want, out there.
If you leave it wide open
or you make it the range too large,
it will try and do its best to
to to get, to the maximum number,
which you may not want,
based off of your cost that you have.
Yeah.
I don't just use CPU utilization.
Use other things as well.
If you've got applications
or microservices
that don't take a lot of CPU,
but maybe a lot of IO, well,
you could overwhelm a microservice
that has tons of IO,
but not a lot of, memory or a lot of CPU.
So take a look
at how your microservices behave
and how you can scale them appropriately.
So take advantage
of those different metrics, right?
Avoid rapid fluctuations.
And with stabilization windows saying,
hey, I need to be stable
for at least, 10 minutes or 30 minutes,
whatever the case may be.
So you're not thrashing,
spitting up and tearing down,
pods all the time, or adding nodes
and things like that.
Have some slack in there,
but also make sure that you can handle,
you know, big events that are happening
and pre-scheduled, those with, some,
cron jobs or with manual, intervention
there.
Okay.
Also, remember that there is startup
time for pods.
They do take some time.
So you've got to make sure
that you build that into things.
So if I have
maybe my threshold is 50 CPU utilization
and my window is a milliseconds.
You could spin up
several replicas of a pod
because the new pods hadn't
come online yet.
So be careful. Those sorts of things.
Also, make sure that you are monitoring
scaling events, and you can use
an external tool like Prometheus
or Grafana to do that sort of stuff.
All right.
Kubernetes has some great, autoscaling,
highly customizable
if you need to both scaling the pods
themselves
and the cluster,
by adding more nodes to it.
Combining HPA, VP and cluster autoscaling
should be something in your, architecture
to make sure that you understand
the difference between horizontal
scaling and vertical scaling
and adding more nodes to your cluster.
So take take a look at all
these when you're designing
your architecture,
whether you're in the cloud or on prem.